Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
- Series X. College History
  - Outside interests, travels, honors
    - Personal correspondence of & about Flora Rose 1906-24 (f1d.3 1931-70, n.d. (fld. 32) (Box 34, Folder 31-32)
    - Correspondence of Flora Rose with Homemakers on food problems, to 1921 (Box 34, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence of Flora Rose with newspaper, magazine and book editors, to 1921 (Box 34, Folder 34)
    - Letters from Flora Rose 1923 (Box 34, Folder 35)
    - Letters - Flora Rose to staff 1928-29 (while at Teachers' College) (Box 34, Folder 36)
    - Letters of Flora Rose to staff 1932-38 (fld. 37); 1940-44 (fld. 38) (Box 34, Folder 37-38)
    - Interview with Flora Rose c. 1953 with Mary Phillips (Box 34, Folder 39)
    - Family Life Course 111, 1929 (Flora Rose) (Box 34, Folder 40)
    - Flora Rose's class notes - Family Life 300 (Box 34, Folder 41)
    - Report on survey of Belgian children - Flora Rose, 1923; note: See also War Relief material (Boxes 17-19); original statistical data (Box 52) collected by Flora Rose during her study of the nutrition of Belgian children following world war I; also 78 oversized folders of statistical sheets arranged by cities; and printed pamphlets (in French) in Box 52 (Box 34, Folder 42-44)
  - Miss Rose's Nutrition Health Study of 5,000 Belgian School Children, 1923
    - Correspondence, criticism of, and outline of thesis; directions for presenting to committee; also includes printed forms used and tables 1922-28 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Chapters I-VI; with photographs of some graphs (Box 52, Folder 2-6)
    - Notes and papers used in thesis (fld. 15 has many pinned pages) (Box 52, Folder 7-18)
    - Tables (Box 52, Folder 19-20)
    - Handwritten and typescript drafts (marked "Kill but Keep") (Box 52, Folder 21-23)
    - Papers on topics including vitamins, insulin, and rickets (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous notes, pages, and papers (Box 52, Folder 25-26)
    - Belgian medals - Museum items, 330-338
    - Applications for housing- Belgian-(oversized), 1923 (Box 40)
      These items were removed from box 52 and transferred to box 40
    - Scrapbook-type item (without covers) - letters to editor of the Delineator, 1922-23 (Box 53)
    - Clippings from the Delineator mounted on oaktag pages, 1919-20 (Box 53)
    - Pages from the Delineator, 1921-23 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Pages from the Delineator, 1919-24 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Clippings from the Delineator(mounted), 1921 (Box 54)
    - "Home Economics Scrap Book for 1923" -Delineator articles, mounted (Box 54)
    - "Home Helps Scrap Book, 1923-25" - mounted Delineator articles (Box 54)
    - Typed list of Delineator articles authored by MVR; loose Delineator articles (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Commission on Rural Homes - Flora Rose, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - International Management Congress - Flora Rose, 1938 (Box 35, Folder 2-3)
    - Milbank Foundation of Cattaraugus County - Flora Rose: 1923-May 1924 (fld. 4); June 1924-January 1925 (fld. 5); February 1925-May 1925 (fld. 5); June-December 1925 (fld. 7) (Box 35, Folder 4-7)
    - Milbank Fund Experiment, Cattaraugus County, continued 1926 (fld. 8); 1927 (fld. 9); 1928, n.d. (fld. 10) (Box 35, Folder 8-10)
    - Milkorns and milkwheats food products - Flora Rose, 1933-34 January-March 1933 (fld. 11); April 1933-March 1934 (fld. 1 April 1934-june 1934, n.d. (fld. 13); n.d. (fld. 14) (Box 35, Folder 11-14)
    - Milk Publicity Bureau - Flora Rose: September 1934-January 1936 (fld. 15); printed material (fld. 16) (Box 35, Folder 15-16)
    - Mount Morris Tuberculosis Sanitorium - Flora Rose, 1939-40 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Rural Electrification Committee - Flora Rose, 1935 (fld- 18) (Box 35, Folder 18-21)
    - World Dairy Congress Association - Flora Rose, 1923 (Box 35, Folder 22)
    - Articles by Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 23)
    - Flora Rose - notes and manuscripts of her speeches; 1923-1938 (fld. 24); n.d. (fld. 25) (Box 35, Folder 24-25)
    - Miss Rose - committees - organizations, subscriptions, etc.1932-1936 (Box 35, Folder 26)
    - Portrait Fund - Miss Rose (Box 35, Folder 27)
    - Miss Rose's portrait (Box 35, Folder 28)
    - Transcription of interview: Miss Flora Rose and Mrs. Mary G. Phillips, October 27, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 29)
    - Personal relationship: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 30)
    - Flora Rose: biographical sketches and data (Box 35, Folder 31)
    - Inauguration of Governor Lehman - Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 32)
    - Resolutions on Miss Rose's retirement - 1940 (Box 35, Folder 33)
    - Flora Rose - Retirement Dinner, 1940: September 1937- June 1940 (folder 34); June 1940-April 1951, n.d. (folder 35) (Box 35, Folder 34-35)
    - Death of Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 36)
    - Clippings about Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 37)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose - appointment as first women professors at Cornell University (Box 35, Folder 38)
    - Manual of Homemaking: Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose - 1914-1915 (fld. 39); 1916-1920 (fld. 40); 1921-1925 (fld. 41); miscellany (fld. 42) (Box 35, Folder 39-42)
    - Tea rooms operated by Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose (Box 35, Folder 43)
    - Mooseheart, (Ill.) Lab. for Child Research: Van Rensselaer, Rose, 1930's - correspondence 1932-1934 (folder 44); conference minutes, 1929 (Eld. 45); 1930 study (folder 46); reports (folder 47); reports, reprints (folder 48) (Box 35, Folder 44-48)
    - Roosevelt Inaugurals - invitations to MVR & FR (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - White House Conference on Child Health, November 19-22, 1930
    - WHC correspondence, 1929 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - WHC correspondence, 1930 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - WHC correspondence, 1931 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - WHC correspondence, 1932 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - White House Conference (Box 56, Folder 5-10)
    - WHC abstracts and papers (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - WHC paper: The Management of Activities and Abilities in the Home; Ruth Lindquist (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - WHC: MVR papers (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - WHC: MVR papers (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - WHC follow-up (Box 57, Folder 2-5)
    - WHC printed material (Box 57, Folder 6-7)
    - WHC Happenings (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - WHC clippings (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Health Education Program reports (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Nutrition Program reports (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Clara Brown (Arney) - evaluation of the College - 1944 (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
    - Home Economics Faculty: Hazel M. Hauck & M. G. Phillips (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Home Economics Faculty: K. Reeves (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Home Economics Faculty: A. J. Warner (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Sarah G. Blanding (fld. 9 includes photographs) (Box 36, Folder 8-9)
    - Sarah Blanding's reception, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 10-11)
    - Dean Helen Canoyer (mostly press releases) (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Early writings on philosophy of Home Economics Education; miscellaneous historical data (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Home Economics at Cornell (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Bill to promote instruction and research in Home Economics 1900 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Outlines of History of Home Economics at Cornell (Box 36, Folder 16-18)
    - Clippings, other mementos of early history of Home Economics at Cornell (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Advisory Group of Citizens Meeting, December 5, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Advisory Group of Citizens Meeting, December 8 & 9, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Advisory Group of Citizens Meeting, December 17, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Advisory Group of Citizens Meeting, January 9, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - MVR and FR awards (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Belgium - Decoration (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Case for Van Rensselaer and Rose medals from Belgium (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Letters from Belgium: Miss Van Rensselaer, Miss Rose, 1923 (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Work in Belgium: Miss Rose & Miss Van Rensselaer - correspondence - including Herbert Hoover, Belgium, etc (Box 36, Folder 28-31)
    - Establishing School of Home Economics - 1919 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - College Bill -- work on, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Advisory Group of Citizens Meeting, November 18 & 19, 1919 (Box 36, Folder 34-36)
    - College Bill work on, 1920 (Box 36, Folder 37-42)
    - College Bill work on, 1921-22 (Box 36, Folder 43)
    - College Bill work on, 1923 (Box 36, Folder 44-49)
    - College Bill work on, 1924 (Box 36, Folder 50-53)
    - College Bill - work on, 1925 (Box 36, Folder 54-55)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - resolutions of organizations (Box 36, Folder 56)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - reports of conferences (Box 36, Folder 57)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - legislative bills (Box 36, Folder 58)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - 1920-21 teaching workreport (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - 1920-21 Extension work (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Proposed College of Home Economics - Advisory Committee (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous data on College Bill (undated) (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Celebration of passage of College Bill, 1925 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - College Annual Report -1909-1910 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - College Annual Report -1910-1911 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - College Annual Report -1912-1913 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - College Annual Report -1913-1914 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - College Annual Report -1915-1916 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - College Annual Report -1916-1917 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - College Annual Report -1917-1918 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - College Annual Report -1917-1920 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - College Annual Report -1918-1919 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - College Annual Report -1919-1920 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - College Annual Report -1920-1921 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - College Annual Report -1921-1922 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - College Annual Report -1922-1923 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - College Annual Report -1923-1924 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Development and Trends in the organization of the New York State College of Home Economics 8/15/36 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - Various reports - 1941 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - "Development of Home Economics at Cornell University" - (photocopy and mimeograph) (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - "Pioneering in Educational Administration" (mostly carbon typescript): pp. 1-50 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - "Pioneering in Educational Administration" - pp. 51-100 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - "Pioneering in Educational Administration" - pp. 101-150 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - "Pioneering in 'Educational Administration" - pp. 151-199 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - Home Economics Faculty Legislation (Box 37, Folder 26)
    - Department of Housing and Design (Box 37, Folder 27)
    - Archives - Department of Housing and Design (Box 37, Folder 28)
    - Departmental Archives - desk file (Box 37, Folder 29)
    - Flora Rose's College History - original - 1940; (with many pins), 1940 annual report (Box 38, Folder 1-7)
    - 1940 Annual Report. A Growing College: Home Economics at Cornell University, Part 11, 1940-1965, by Esther H. Stocks. (carbon typescript) (Box 38, Folder 8-14)
    - Notes by Martha Van Rensselaer about herself (Box 38, Folder 15)
- Series XI: Photographs
  - Photographs from box 39 are available on-line
  - Oversize Photographs
    - Winter Course 1912-13. Some of those in the front row are staff. From left, they are: _____, ____, ____, Helen Knowlton, Helen Binkerd Young, Martha Van Renssealer, Liberty Hyde Bailey, Flora Rose, Clara Browning, Anna Hunn, _____, _____, _____, _____ (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Winter Course, 1914-15 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Winter Course, 1912-13 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Foods Laboratory (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Foods Laboratory (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Formal Dinner (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Broadside mock-up (with photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer): Martha Van Rensselaer Collection of Books. The gift of the Home Bureau Agents of New York State (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Etching done by Anna Botsford Comstock. (Series XIII) (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript of "Candle-Lighting" song (with descriptive letter). (Series XIII) (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Mounted photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer, 1928 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Mounted photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer, Spring 1919 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Mounted photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Mounted photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer: A good likeness, and a photograph that both Miss Van Rensselaer and Miss Rose considered good. circa 1912-14 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Mounted photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Mounted copy of Martha Van Rensselaer's portrait (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Mounted photograph of Madame Curie, with annotated calling card (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Mural, College of Home Economics, 1939 World's Fair
    - Correspondence, transparency and lists Negatives for pictures labeled: left side of mural (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - 8x10 a. people sitting in living room b. family making home-made articles in recreational room c. girls studying in library d. clothes fitting and modeling e. class in pillow and mattress making (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - 8x10 a. lesson in serving b. food preparing (cafeteria kitchen) c. home planning d. instruction in table setting e. mother and children busy in nursery (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Negatives for pictures labeled: right-side of mural
    - 8x10 a. aerial vieew of group of buildings b. community kitchen c. family group d. buying and inspection of furniture e. family at: work in kitchen (grooming clothes) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - 8x10 a. class sitting around dining table b. clothes buying c. preserving fruits d. woman at growing counter e. watching Dutch girls arrange a tea table (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - 8x10 a. hanging of draperies and curtains b. two teachers and a group of children eating c. putting partitions in kitchen cabinet d. nurse checking baby's health e. year's vegetable needs for one person­ (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - 8x10 a. "spic and span" kitchen b. kitchen planning c. woman and child in toy shop d. children eating e. people attending State Federation of Home Bureaus Exhibits f. aerial view of small community (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Other Negatives
    - 8x10 "Food Weighting." Student in research laboratory: (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - 4x5 Extension-demonstration on foundation garments, probably around 1915-1918 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - 4x5 Demonstration of use of dress form (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - 4x5 Health exercises at recess under direction of a teacher (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - 4x5 Pratt Institute (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - 4x5 Main business office in home economics building, 1924 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - 4x5 Onondaga Indian women can vegetables (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - 4x5 Home Bureau (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - 4x5 Extension demonstration on use of dress form (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - 4x5 Farmers' Wives Club around 1915.' (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - 4x5 Junior Extension food demonstration, around 1920's (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - 4x5 Rural school children brushing teeth, around 1918 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - 4x5 Cooking laboratory, around 1915-20 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - 4x5 Home economics laboratory, around 1910-20 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - 4x5 Foods laboratory, Winter Course, 1909-11 (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - 4x5 Weighing and measuring local school children, around 1918 (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - 4x5 Monthly visit of Extension agent to local school (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - 4x5 Nutrition clinic in local school, around 1918 (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - 4x5 Home economics cafeteria, around 1915 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - 4x5 Noon hour in home economics cafeteria, around 1915 (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - 4x5 Series showing how child can help in home, no date (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - 4x5 After dinner at Lodge, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - 4x5 Naptime for Lodge baby, 1918-20 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - 4x5 Laboratory and drafting room for housing and design (Comstock Hall), 1920 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - 4x5 Christmas in Lodge apartment, around 1920. This negative is backwards -- should always be printed emulsion up (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - 4x5 Living room of Lodge used for homemaking practice, around 1920 (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - 4x5 Exterior of Lodge, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - 4x5 Senior night ceremony, around 1920 (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - 4x5 Float in unidentified parade, around 1915-20 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - 4x5 Afternoon tea in homemaking apartment, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - 4x5 Institution management students inspect local warehouse, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - 4x5 Ruth Kellogg, shoulder seams, around 1918 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - 4x5 School exhibit on value of milk, around 1918 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - 4x5 Cooking class in school of Home Economics, around 1920 (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - 4x5 Domestic science room at James E. Yeaton High School, St. Louis, MO (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - 4x5 Home economics at other schools (Box 41, Folder 43-47)
    - 4x5 Correspond to proofs on index cards, Box 39, folder 48.No. 1278 (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - 4x5 No. 4849 (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - 4x5 No. 4850 (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - 4x5 No. 4851 (Box 41, Folder 51)
    - 4x5 No. 4852 (Box 41, Folder 52)
    - 4x5 No. 4853 (Box 41, Folder 53)
    - 4x5 No. 4854 (Box 41, Folder 54)
    - 4x5 No. 4855 (Box 41, Folder 55)
    - 4x5 No. 4856 (Box 41, Folder 56)
    - 4x5 No. 4857 (Box 41, Folder 57)
    - 4x5 No.4890 (Box 41, Folder 58)
    - 4x5 Unidentified negatives, exteriors (Box 41, Folder 59-61)
    - 4x5 Unidentified negatives, interior laboratory scenes (Box 41, Folder 62-64)
    - 4x5 Unidentified negatives, interior classroom and lecture scenes (Box 41, Folder 65-66)
    - various Miscellaneous unidentified negatives (Box 41, Folder 67)
    - 4x5 Series on child helping in the home (Box 41, Folder 68)
    - 4x5 Building floor plans (Box 41, Folder 69)
    - 4x5 Martha Van Rensselaer Hall & Martha Van Rensselaer (Box 41, Folder 70)
    - 5x7 Martha Van Rensselaer family. Corresponds to Box 55, Folder 2, Item 26. Possibly nitrate (Box 41, Folder 71)
    - 5x7 Martha Van Rensselaer. Corresponds to Box 55, Folder 2, Item 27. Possibly nitrate (Box 41, Folder 72)
    - Oversize Glass Negatives Concerning Food Preparation (Box 106, Folder 1-5)
    - 3 boxes of Oversize Glass Negatives (5.5" x 7.5")of Nursery School Children, 1931-1932 (Box 59)
    - Two file boxes of color slides: Practice House and Nutrition Class Youngsters, ca. 1944 (Box 42)
    - Glass Slides (Box 43)
  - Martha Van Rensselaer
    - Scanned photographs from Box 55, CD-#748 (Box 108)
    - Portrait of General Solomon Van Rensselaer, half-brother of David S. Van Rensselaer, who was Martha Van Rensselaer's grandfather, 1 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Portrait of K.K. Van Rensselaer, a close relative (brother?) of Solomon, 2 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - David S. Van Rensselaer, M.D., a homeopathic physician and grandfather of Martha Van Rensselaer. Tintype, 3 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Minnie Seager Van Rensselaer, of Randolph, NY, an unidentified relative of Martha Van Rensselaer, 4 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - All portraits of Arvilla Gwen Van Rensselaer, mother of Martha Van Rensselaer, 5-13 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - All portraits of Henry Killian Van Rensselaer, father of Martha Van Rensselaer, 14-16 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Paired portraits of Martha Van Rensselaer's parents in black, padded folder, 17 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Ellen E. Van Rensselaer, half-sister of Martha Van Rensselaer, 18 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Killian Van Rensselaer as an infant. Relationship is not given, but name is an old family one, used many times, 19-20 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - _____ Owen, an uncle of Martha Van Rensselaer, 21 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Heavily lacquered photograph of Martha Van Rensselaer as a young woman, with Jessie Owen, whose relationship is not given, 22 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Supposedly Martha Van Rensselaer as an infant, but identification is questioned on photo, 23 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer as a young girl, with brothers Leland (older) and Herbert. These three were all of the children born to Henry Killian and Arvilla Owen Van Rensselaer, 24 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Photo arid enlargement of Martha and Leland Van Rensselaer as young children, 25-26 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer as a young girl, 27 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Miniature of Item 27, 28. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Inscription in Martha Van Rensselaer's hand writing reads, "Martha Van Rensselaer - Beginning high school and feeling older than she does now. ", 29 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Martha and Herbert Van Rensselaer as young adults, 30 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer (with flowers) as young woman, 31 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Assorted portraits of Martha Van Rensselaer as a young woman, 32-50 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer, Julia Kepler and Mae Neal taken when they were teaching together in the public schools at Tidioute, PA, 51 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer by "The Misses Lilby"; 1908, 52 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Copies of portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer as older.- woman; by Brandenburg Studio, 53-55 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Copies of portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer by Harris and Ewing which was used in book-plate. Miss Van Rensselaer is wearing the dress she wore to sit for the portrait which hangs in the faculty lounge. This dress is now part of the historic costume collection of the Department of Textiles and Clothing., 56-59 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer, undated portrait, 60 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Copy of memorial bookplate for the Martha Van Rensselaer Collection of Books, housed in Mann Library, 61 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Plate containing Harris and Ewing portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer on one side and fore word by Dean Carl Ladd of the College of Agriculture on the other; used in 1940 annual report of College, 62 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Photograph of portrait painting of Martha Van Rensselaer which hangs in faculty lounge. Artist is Lydia Field Emmet. Dress is changed and given fur collar, 63 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Sepia portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer by White Studio. This was used as the frontis piece in: Percival, Carolyn, MARTHA VAN RENS- SELAER, Ithaca, New York, 1957, published by the AlUmnae Assocation of the New York State College of Home Economics at Cornell University, 26p, 64 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Glossy copies of Item 64, 65-66 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Two copies of portrait of Martha Van Rensselaer taken in May 1927, 67-68 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer at her desk; apparently taken about the same time as Items 67-68. (There are similarities in costume and arrange ment of hair.) Missing, 69 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Sepia snapshot of Martha Van Rensselaer as young woman seated in parlor, 70 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Stage setting, with Martha Van Rensselaer standing at far right, 71 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Group of girls in long, white dresses, re clining on rug. Martha Van Rensselaer is the topmost one. Missing, 72 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose in out door setting with mart dressed as clown (per haps Clio-Cho, of the Child Health organization), 73 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Snapshot of Martha Van Rensselaer (in striped jacket) with group, hiking, 74 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer (in striped jacket and gym shoes) hiking with Flora Rose in New England, 75 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Martha Van Rensselaer hiking in White Mountains, 76 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Blue print of Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose in camping dress sitting on log and eating, 77 (Box 55, Folder 4)